<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neural networks on Vicente Lisboa</title>
    <link>https://vicentelisboa.github.io/tags/neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neural networks on Vicente Lisboa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vicentelisboa.github.io/tags/neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic classification of Yahoo Answers using deep learning models</title>
      <link>https://vicentelisboa.github.io/post/project--2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vicentelisboa.github.io/post/project--2/</guid>
      <description>Classification of Yahoo Answers Introduction The goal of this project is to classify Yahoo! Answers posts into their respective topics. We use a dataset provided by Huggingface, which includes 2 million Yahoo! Answers posts categorized into ten topics. We select three topics - Health, Science &amp;amp; Mathematics, and Society &amp;amp; Culture - and sample 100,000 posts from the dataset for training and testing.
We apply several models to the task of classification, including rule-based models, traditional machine learning models, and deep learning models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability of death and length of stay using MIMIC dataset</title>
      <link>https://vicentelisboa.github.io/post/project--3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vicentelisboa.github.io/post/project--3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following project has two objectives:
Predict the probability of death of a patient that is entering an ICU (Intensive Care Unit) using K-Nearest Neighbors (KNN) and Support Vector Machine (SVM) models. Predict the length of stay (in days) of a patient that is entering an ICU using decision tree, ensembles and neural networks models. Dataset description The dataset comes from MIMIC project (https://mimic.physionet.org/). MIMIC-III (Medical Information Mart for Intensive Care III) is a large, freely-available database comprising deidentified health-related data associated with over forty thousand patients who stayed in critical care units of the Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center between 2001 and 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
